<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><chapter id="sylpheed-1">
  <title>What is Sylpheed?</title>
  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="snapshots/full_split.png" format="PNG"/>
    </imageobject>
  </mediaobject>
  <section>
    <title>Introduction to Sylpheed</title>
    <para>Sylpheed is a fast e-mail and news client. It will run on just
      about any Linux or Unix compliant system.</para>
    <para>Sylpheed is:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Light on system resources.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Very fast.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>easy to learn and operate, due to its graceful and
          sophisticated interface.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Loaded with features.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Main features</title>
    <para>This list is not complete, but the most common features of
      Sylpheed are:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Unlimited multiple account handling</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Thread display</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Filtering</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>MIME (attachments)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>built-in image view</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>X-Face support</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>External editor support</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Message queueing</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Draft message function</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Template</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Line-wrapping</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Clickable URI</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>XML-based addressbook</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>LDAP addressbook</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Jpilot addressbook (for Palm types handhelds)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Newly arrived and unread message management</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Multiple MH folder support</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Mew/Wanderlust compatible key bindings</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>News reader function</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Printing</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>UIDL support</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>APOP authentication</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>SMTP AUTH support</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>IPv6 support</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>GPG encryption and signature</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Autoconf, automake support</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Support of i18n of messages by gettext</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Supports many locales, including UTF-8 (Unicode), when using
          libjconv</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>IMAP4 compliant</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Methods for managing messages</title>
    <para>There are several ways to manage messages. The best known is
      <quote>not at all</quote>.</para>
    <para>Many people receive an unmanageable amount of e-mail, which
      usually ends up in the INBOX folder, ignored and forgotten. If you are
      one of these people, you are constantly trying to locate that one
      important email you got 5 days ago in a inbox that contains more than
      5000 messages. Locating one email out of very many unsorted messages is
      always a time-consuming and frustrating experience.</para>
    <para>Sylpheed helps this situation with its mailfolders and
      mailboxes.</para>
    <para>Different mailboxes can store different kinds of mails. Suppose
      you are a member of a kiting club, and you get at least 30 e-mails per
      day from that club. You can create a separate kiting club mailbox, in
      which you can move any e-mail that comes from this club. You will always
      have all your kiting e-mails in one place.</para>
    <para>Tedious, you say, to move 30 mails a day to that box, when email
      comes in at random moments? It is certain that you will miss that very
      important email about transport to the kiting ground where you will have
      the contest of biggest and most beautiful kite!</para>
    <para>Well, for this situation there is also a solution- filters.</para>
    <para>Filters can automate the process of moving e-mails to new
      mailboxes. Further on in this manual you will also learn about setting
      up filters, so you do not have to manually move these kiting e-mails to
      the kiting club mailbox.</para>
    <section>
      <title>Okay, so what is the difference between a mailbox and a mailfolder?</title>
      <para>This is the same way you organize information on your harddisk.
        You create directories in which you put files or more
        directories.</para>
      <para>In Sylpheed, you can create mailboxes within mailboxes For
        example, you could create a mailbox (folder) that contains the
        mailboxes for all the different mailing lists to which you belong
        .</para>
      <para>A word of clarification- In Sylpheed, a maillbox is nothing more
        than a directory. In a directory you can create either a new directory
        or files. Sylpheed stores each e-mail in a separate file on disk. An
        example of how a mailbox tree could look is</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="snapshots/folder_tree.png" format="PNG"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>As you can see, there is no real limit to the way you
        can set up your mailboxes. As long as you have diskspace available,
        you can create mailboxes and mailboxes within mailboxes.</para>
      <para>Of course, you should observe some common sense when you start
        creating mailboxes. It is not a good idea to keep all mail in one
        place but to create a maze of mailboxes is not a good idea
        either!</para>
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>