<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><chapter id="sylpheed-6">
  <title>The menu options of Sylpheed</title>
  <para>
The menu in Sylpheed is the primary entry to all the things 
you can do with Sylpheed. The menu structure gives you following 
options:
</para>
  <section>
    <title>File menu</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Add mailbox:</computeroutput> this option lets you add a new MH mail-directory. 
  It will generate IN, OUT, QUEUE, DRAFT and TRASH mailfolders 
  inside the new mailbox.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Check for new messages in all folders:</computeroutput> rescans the entire tree 
  of existing mailboxes to reflect the correct state (usually 
  won&apos;t be necessary).</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Folder:</computeroutput> lets you add, rename or delete a mailfolder.</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Create new folder:</computeroutput> to create a new folder. You must select
    the top level node of the folder tree of a sub folder before
    using this menu entry, in order to define the location of the
    new folder to create.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Rename folder:</computeroutput> change the name of the selected folder.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Delete folder:</computeroutput> delete the selected folder (also delete the
    messages contained in the selected folder).</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Import mbox file...:</computeroutput> lets you import an mbox file 
  (like created by Pine) into an MH mailbox.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Export to mbox file:</computeroutput> lets you export an MH mailbox to an mbox file.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Empty trash:</computeroutput> obviously, this will empty the trash folder.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Save as:</computeroutput> lets you save the selected e-mail to a plain textfile 
  on disk.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Print:</computeroutput> lets you print the selected e-mail to a printer.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Exit:</computeroutput> ends Sylpheed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Edit menu </title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>copy:</computeroutput> lets you copy the selected text to a buffer, 
  from where you can paste it into a different place. 
  Shortcut: Ctrl-C</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>select all:</computeroutput> selects all the text in the current window. 
  Shortcut: Ctrl-A</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>select thread:</computeroutput> selects all the messages of the current thread.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Find in current message:</computeroutput> searches a string in the current message.
  Shortcut: Ctrl-F</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>search messages:</computeroutput> searches a message based on its  To, From, Subject
  header fields or body content. Start searching from the selected
  message, in the selected folder. 
  Shortcut: Shift-Ctrl-F</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>View menu </title>
    <para>
The view menu allows you to change the way that Sylpheed appears. 
You can set different windows separately (folder view, messages etc.), 
enable or disable the statusbar and so on.
It contains also the commands to toggle the display of some parts
of the current message, or sort the messsages in the selected folder
based on different attributes.
</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Show or hide:</computeroutput> let you control the parts of the Sylpheed user interface 
  you want to display.</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Folder tree:</computeroutput> not implemented yet</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Message view:</computeroutput> show or hide the message pane. When hidden, the
    messages are displayed in a separate window. To read a message
    double click in the summary pane. The message is then opened in
    a new window. You can close this new window by pressing the escape
    key.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Toolbar:</computeroutput> sets how you want to see the toolbar. Icons and text, 
    or one of these.</para>
            <itemizedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>
      <computeroutput>Icon and Text:</computeroutput> show icons and text in the toolbar.</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>
      <computeroutput>Icon:</computeroutput> only display the icons, do not display the text
      below them.</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>
      <computeroutput>Text:</computeroutput> only the text, hide the icons.</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>
      <computeroutput>None:</computeroutput> hide the toolbar.</para>
              </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Status bar:</computeroutput> show it or hide it.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Separate folder tree:</computeroutput> selects between having the folder tree 
  attached to the main window, or floating separately.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Separate message view:</computeroutput> selects between having the selected 
  message in the summary pane attached to the main window, or 
  floating separately.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Sort:</computeroutput> controls the way the messages are sorted in the selected
  folder. Each option sorts the messages in descending order (the
  bigger one being on the top of the summary pane), and can be
  reversed by selecting the same menu entry a second time (each
  time you select the same menu entry the order is reversed).</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Sort by number:</computeroutput> sort the message based on their MH number.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Sort by size:</computeroutput> sort the message on their size.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Sort by date:</computeroutput> sort the messages based on their date.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Sort by from:</computeroutput> the messages are sorted by their sender address
    (From field, sorted alphabetically).</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Sort by recipient:</computeroutput> the messages are sorted by their recipient
    (sorted alphabetically).</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Sort by subject:</computeroutput> the messages are sorted by their subject
    (sorted alphabetically).</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Sort by color label:</computeroutput> sort the messages based on their color.
    Read the context menu description below to find how to assign
    colors to messages.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Sort by mark:</computeroutput> separate marked and unmarked messages. Read the 
    context menu description below to find how to mark messages.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Sort by unread:</computeroutput> separate read and unread messages.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Sort by attachment:</computeroutput> separate messages with and without attachment.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Don&apos;t sort:</computeroutput> do not sort the messages.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Ascending:</computeroutput> sort the messages in ascending order. If the field used
    to sort the messages is displayed in the summary view, a little
    arrow on the right side of the corresponding summay column header
    reflects the sort order you select from the menu.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Descending:</computeroutput> sort the messages in descending order.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Attract by subject:</computeroutput> move close to each other the messages
    having the same subject (or a close subject).</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Thread view:</computeroutput> turn the threaded view on or off. When turned on the
  messages of the same thread (the same discussion generated by replying
  to each other mail) are grouped as a tree representing the discussion
  flow. Each reply being linked to its orignal message. Each branch can
  be open or closed by using the small plus or minus sign next to it.
  The threads are based on the In-Reply-To and Reference fields of the
  mail header, so never start a new conversation by replying to an
  old message, this will add your new mail to the old unrelated thread.
  Shortcut: Ctrl-T</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Expand all threads:</computeroutput> if the threaded view is selected, expand all the
  threads in the opened folder.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Collapse all threads:</computeroutput> if the threaded view is selected, collapse all the
  threads in the opened folder.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Set display item:</computeroutput> use it to change the list of items to display
  in the summary view. This setting can also be changed through
  the common preferences.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Go to:</computeroutput> use it to navigate from message to message based on the
  sub-menu criterias.</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Prev. message:</computeroutput> go to the previous message in the current
    folder.
    Shortcut: P</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Next message:</computeroutput> go to the next message in the current
    folder.
    Shortcut: N</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Prev. unread:</computeroutput> go to the previous unread message.
    Shortcut: Shift-P</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Next unread:</computeroutput> go to the next unread message.
    Shortcut: Shift-N</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Prev. new:</computeroutput> go to the previous new message.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Next new:</computeroutput> go to the next new message.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Prev. marked:</computeroutput> go to the previous marked message.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Next marked:</computeroutput> go to the next marked message.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Prev. labeled:</computeroutput> go to the previous labeled message.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Next labeled:</computeroutput> go to the next labeled message.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Other folder:</computeroutput> change the current folder. Opens a new window
    with the folder tree, and open the selected folder.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Code set:</computeroutput> allows you to select what codeset you want to use 
  for your e-mails. This codeset will be used when sending
  mails. Note Sylpheed will always try to use the more compatible
  codeset based on the characters used in your message, so unless
  you use special latin-1 characters in your mail, the encoding
  will be defined as 7bits ASCII even if you have selected the
  ISO-8859-1 character set.
  The auto-detect option let Sylpheed automatically detect the
  character set based on the content of the messages.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Open in new window:</computeroutput> open the selected message in a new window.
  This new window can be closed by pressing the escape key.
  Shortcut: Ctrl-Alt-N</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Message source:</computeroutput> opens a new window and display the complete
  source of the message in it (without any formatting and with
  all the header fields).
  Shortcut: Ctrl-U</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Show all header:</computeroutput> toggles on and off the display of the complete
  message header.
  Shortcut: Ctrl-H</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Update summary:</computeroutput> update the Sylpheed window.
  Shortcut: Ctrl-Alt-U</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Message menu </title>
    <para>
Here you find the following options:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Get new mail:</computeroutput> this will collect all new mail for your 
  default mail-identity.
  Shortcut: Ctrl-I</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Get from all accounts:</computeroutput> Sylpheed will poll all defined 
  mail-identities for new mail.
  Shortcut: Shift-Ctrl-I</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Cancel receiving:</computeroutput> stop the new mails reception.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Send queued messages:</computeroutput> all the messages that you put into 
  the &quot;Queue&quot; folder will now be sent off.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Compose new message:</computeroutput> allows you to write a new e-mail 
  message.
  Shortcut: Ctrl-M</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Reply:</computeroutput> an e-mail message will be created with the sender 
  of the selected message in the summary pane as recipient. 
  Depending on the settings, your signature will be added 
  to the mail, and the original mail text will be quoted.
  If a part of the original mail is selected, only this
  part will be quoted in the reply.
  Shortcut: Ctrl-R</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Reply to</computeroutput> </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>all:</computeroutput> as Reply, but the recipients will be all 
    e-mail addresses in the original messages (including 
    the ones in the cc: part).
    Shortcut: Shift-Ctrl-R</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>sender:</computeroutput> as Reply.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Mailing list:</computeroutput> reply to the mailing list. To use
    when replying to a mailing list (unless you want to reply
    only to the poster of the message).
    Shortcut: Ctrl-L</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  Reply to sender: as Reply, but the recipient is the address
  defined in the Sender header field (not the Reply-To address).</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Forward:</computeroutput> a message will be created with the original 
  message in the summary pane as text. You can then 
  enter a recipient e-mail address, edit the text if 
  you want, and send it.
  Shortcut: Ctrl-Alt-F</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Forward as attachment:</computeroutput> as Forward, but the message 
  text will sent along as a separate textfile.
  Shortcut: Shift-Ctrl-Alt-F</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Redirect:</computeroutput> re-send the selected message to someone else. Compared
  to a forward, the message is not marked as forwarded, and the sender
  is the original mail sender.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Re-edit:</computeroutput> lets you open all already sent message in
  edition mode to re-send it.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Move:</computeroutput> lets you move the message to a different folder. 
  You can select the destination folder from a browse-window.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Copy:</computeroutput> as Move, only that the message is copied to the 
  new folder, instead of moved.
  Shortcut: Shift-Ctrl-O</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Delete:</computeroutput> lets you delete the message that is selected 
  in the summary pane.
  Shortcut: Ctrl-D</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Mark:</computeroutput> Gives a submenu: <computeroutput>Mark/Unmark/Mark as read/Unmark as read</computeroutput>. When you mark messages, you can do a specific 
  action (e.g. move, delete) on all of the marked messages. 
  You can unmark messages that you mistakenly marked. 
  The other options do as they say, they mark or unmark 
  a message as read, and mark all read, marks all the messages
  of the current folder as read.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
A note on functions like Move, Copy and Delete: if you did not 
specify to execute the commands immediately (in the configuration), 
you will have to select the <computeroutput>Execute</computeroutput> command. This is a button 
in the toolbar, and can also be found in the Summary menu.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Tool menu </title>
    <para>
In the Tool menu are grouped the filters control, address book
access and log window control.</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Address book:</computeroutput> opens the address book window.
  Shortcut: Shift-Ctrl-A</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Add sender to address book:</computeroutput> adds the sender of the selected
  message to one of your address books. When selected a window
  opens to let you select the target address book.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Filter messages:</computeroutput> apply the filter rules to the messages
  of the inbox.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Create filter rule:</computeroutput> create a new filter rule based on the
  selected message.</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>Automatically:</computeroutput> open the filter rules creation window
    to define a new rule.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>By From:</computeroutput> opens the filter rules creation window and
    fills the filter settings fields to build a filter based
    on the sender of the selected message.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>By To:</computeroutput> opens the filter rules creation window and
    fills the filter settings fields to build a filter based
    on the receiver of the selected message.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
    <computeroutput>By Subject:</computeroutput> opens the filter rules creation window and
    fills the filter settings fields to build a filter based
    on the subject of the selected message.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Actions:</computeroutput> this menu is empty until you define some actions (see the
  configuration menu description).</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Delete duplicated messages:</computeroutput> This will remove messages from the 
  active folder that were sent twice to you. For example you 
  received a message directly and through a mailing list at 
  the same time.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Execute:</computeroutput> execute all the pending move, delete, and copy commands.
  Only if execute immediately is off in the common preferences.
  Shortcut: X</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Log window:</computeroutput> opens the log window. In the log window, you 
  can see what Sylpheed is doing. Keeping track of things 
  in that way is very good when you suspect there is something 
  wrong. You can paste the info of the log window into an 
  e-mail and send it to the developer or the mailing list.
  Shortcut: Shift-Ctrl-L</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
In the log window, you can see what Sylpheed is doing. Keeping 
track of things in that way is very good when you suspect there 
is something wrong. You can paste the info of the log window 
into an e-mail and send it to the developer or the mailing list.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Configuration menu </title>
    <para>
In the Configuration menu, clearly, you can set up Sylpheed 
the way you want it to work and react.</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Common preferences:</computeroutput> in this option you will be 
  presented a dialog in which you can select a number 
  of tabs. Each tab represents a specific set of settings 
  in Sylpheed. In the next chapter, these dialog options 
  are explained in more detail.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Filter setting:</computeroutput> this option shows you a dialog in which you 
  can set up the filtering rules that you want Sylpheed 
  to process on receiving new e-mails. You first specify 
  on which part(s) of the e-mail Sylpheed has to check, 
  and then you tell Sylpheed what to do. You can move the 
  message to a different directory (including trash to get 
  rid of spam mail). Selecting the destination folder is 
  possible through a browser window that comes up when you 
  press &quot;Select...&quot;
  </para>
        <para>
  You can choose not to receive the e-mail. Note that 
  this will leave the message on the mailserver of your 
  provider, the message will not be removed!
  </para>
        <para>
  When you press the &quot;Register&quot; button, the filter 
  rule is added to the list of rules. Do you select 
  &quot;Substitute&quot;, then the selected rule is replaced by the 
  information of the setting entered. &quot;Delete&quot; in the end 
  will delete the selected filtering rule.
  </para>
        <para>
  Please note that you can set up two selections for a rule, 
  which can be &quot;OR&apos;d&quot; or &quot;AND&apos;d&quot;. OR means that one of the 
  two selections will have to match for the rule to be 
  executed. AND means that both selections have to match 
  before an action is performed.
  </para>
        <para>
  To the right of the selection rules you see buttons 
  called UP and DOWN. You can move rules up and down in 
  the list. This will often trigger different behaviour 
  in the selections, so consider the order in which 
  you set the rules.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Template:</computeroutput> let your create a new message template.
  When composing a new message you can then used one
  of the defined templates and insert it (or use it to
  completely replace the content of your mail).
  The templates can contain some special characters
  that are replaced when the template is used in order
  to create a dynamic text. Use the symbols button on
  the templates definition window to see the list of
  the available symbols.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Actions:</computeroutput> let your create new commands to be added to the
  &apos;Tools/Actions&apos; menu. An action is a command that processes
  the select part of a message, the message body or the complete
  message file. It can be a background process, used as a filter
  (reads, modifies and replaces a message),...</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Preferences for current account:</computeroutput> here you can set the 
  specifics for the account you are currently using. 
  Should mail be deleted after fetching, what is the 
  server it comes from, etc. Basically it is the same 
  dialog form as shown in setting up a new account.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Create new account:</computeroutput> here you name the account (each 
  account has a recognizable name), you set up your name 
  and e-mail address etc. You set up the type of server 
  you access (POP4, IMAP4, local mailbox, newsserver) 
  and where the downloaded messages have to go (default 
  folder is the inbox). In the RECEIVE tab you select or 
  unselect options, in SEND you can set up how to send 
  your messages. In COMPOSE you can point to a specific 
  signature file, and in ADVANCED you can set up alternate 
  ports for the server, if these exist. (Do not mess 
  with these unless you are sure you have to!!)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Edit accounts:</computeroutput> here you can select one of the accounts 
  you created, from a list, and edit the information about 
  them. Note that you cannot edit an account for which 
  you are writing a message at the same time. This to 
  ensure data integrity.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
  <computeroutput>Change current account:</computeroutput> here you can select what 
  account you want to use, to write a message.
  If you have enabled the status bar (in the view menu),
  the name of the current account is shown in the bottom
  right corner of the Sylpheed window (in the status bar)
  and can be changed by a click on it (then a menu appears
  and lists all your accounts).</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Help menu </title>
    <para>
This menu lets you look at the manual and FAQ of Sylpheed, 
and you can also see the &quot;about&quot; info, who wrote Sylpheed.
</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Context menu </title>
    <para>
You can pull up context menus (through clicking button2) for 
the folder tree and the summary pane. (windows users: button2 
is the right mouse button.)
</para>
    <para>
In the folder view you can add, rename and remove folders 
through the context menu. You can also set the folder
properties (define the selected folder as an inbox, outbox,
trash, ...).
</para>
    <para>
In the message summary you can do a host of things from the 
context menu, like viewing message headers, opening a message 
in a separate window (also possible by double clicking on a 
message) etc...
</para>
  </section>
</chapter>