<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><chapter id="sylpheed-19">
  <title>Information</title>
  <section>
    <title>Websites on Sylpheed</title>
    <para>Here are some links to the Sylpheed FAQ in other languages:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink url="http://sylpheeddoc.sourceforge.net/fr/faq/faq.html">Sylpheed FAQ in French</ulink>, translated by Olivier Delhomme.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink url="http://sylpheeddoc.sourceforge.net/de/faq/faq.html">Sylpheed FAQ in German</ulink>, translated by Nicolas Kaiser.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink url="http://sylpheeddoc.sourceforge.net/es/faq/faq.html">Sylpheed FAQ in Spanish</ulink>, translated by Ricardo  Mones Lastra.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><ulink url="http://sylpheeddoc.sourceforge.net/zh_TW.Big5/sylpheed-faq.html">Sylpheed FAQ in Traditional Chinese</ulink>, courtesy of Franklin.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>
        You can always download the English FAQ from the <ulink url="http://sylpheeddoc.sourceforge.net/en/faq/sylpheed-faq.html">Sylpheed Documentation Project website</ulink>.</para>
        <note>
          <para>Did not find your language in the list? Would you like to contribute with a new translation to the Sylpheed Documentation Project? Then please contact the Project members at <ulink url="http://sylpheeddoc.sourceforge.net/">their website</ulink>. Thanks in advance.</para>
        </note>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Mailing Lists</title>
    <para>
If you want to stay up to date on Sylpheed, and want to talk about the program with other users, you can join the mailing list.</para>
    <para>
Send a mail to sylpheed-ctl@good-day.net that says</para>
    <para>
<guilabel>subscribe Your Name</guilabel></para>
    <para>
in the body.</para>
    <para>
The server returns the mail once for the first registration request that asks the confirmation: &quot;May I put you on this mailing list?&quot; that includes the following phrase (this number is merely an example).</para>
    <para>
<guilabel>confirm 84682771 Anne Shirley</guilabel></para>
    <para>
This is a precaution for mischief like subscribing you to the list against your wish.</para>
    <para>
If you received the entry confirmation mail, send a mail that includes the phrase:</para>
    <para>
<guilabel>confirm Password(a number) Your Name</guilabel></para>
    <para>
to the address for registration: sylpheed-ctl@good-day.net again. Then, it is considered that you have confirmed the registration and you are registered to the server.</para>
    <para>
The address for posting to the list is sylpheed@good-day.net.</para>
    <para>
Notice: If you lost the mail that says</para>
    <para>
confirm Password(a number) Your Name</para>
    <para>
or you became confused and want to do from start, do them over from the start, in other words, send</para>
    <para>
<guilabel>subscribe Anne Shirley</guilabel></para>
    <para>
to sylpheed-ctl@good-day.net again.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>How to unsubscribe.</title>
    <para>
Send a mail to sylpheed-ctl@good-day.net that says</para>
    <para>
<guilabel>unsubscribe</guilabel></para>
    <para>
in the body.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Anonymous CVS</title>
    <para>
This section has not been written yet.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
